[♪♪♪]
[screeching with effort]
[yelping]
Do not be afraid to fail, Riyu,
for every time we fail,
we learn.
[grumbling]
Has anyone seen Cole,
Kai, or Frak?
When I sent them elsewhere
to train,
I didn't mean for forever.
[Frak] How is it night already?
It felt like we barely
had any sun today.
Are we there yet?
[Kai] Yeah, I thought
Master Wu's ghost or whatever
showed you where this thing was.
I was hearing his call.
It's not like the ghost voice
drew me a map!
The terrain out here
seems different.
Could the Realms
still be shifting
after the Merge?
[Kai] Who knows?
Maybe that explains
why it's dark out already.
There! That's it!
[♪♪♪]
Looks like
there was an epic party here
a long time ago,
or maybe a battle.
One of the two.
Huh.
[wincing] Ah!
The feeling's so strong here.
The Earth itself is crying out.
This has to be
where it's coming from.
Maybe what I couldn't do
by myself,
we can do together.
Hope this works...
unless whatever
you're pulling up is evil,
in which case, I hope you fail.
No way Master Wu's voice
would try to get Cole
to dig up something evil.
I mean, right?
Master Wu apparently
caused the Merge
for some reason, so who knows?
[munching and gagging]
If you hate Geo's wafers
so much,
why are you still eating them?
[sighing] I keep hoping
they'll eventually taste good.
[munching and coughing]
There, Frak, can you feel it?
There's something huge
down there.
[gasping]
It's hard to sense anything
over all the screaming--
Wait, is this...?
You got it.
I feel your quake.
What could it be?
Oh, it's massive.
Only one way to find out.
Pull!
[ground crumbling]
I think it's working.
[straining]
Is it a jet?
A-a-a building?
Whoa...
[munching and gagging]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[slurping]
Ah...
Moss milk ice cream
never tasted so good.
A frozen delight.
Sora, this stuff's
only okay at best.
Ah, I guess
barely escaping with your life
from a crazed tiger dude
who wants to shut you
into a Casket of Bones
makes everything taste better.
[slurping]
Okay, I'm getting another one,
but then we gotta find a way
to help those poor hollow people
in Mysterium.
Should we head back
to the Monastery
and tell the others?
Yeah...
Not sure they're gonna
be happy to see me, though.
Trust me,
everyone misses you.
Listen, there's somewhere
I need to go first.
Only problem is,
we can't get there on bikes.
Let me see what I can do.
[♪♪♪]
[marching feet]
I didn't even know
this place had weapons.
I'm impressed.
Thanks for giving us
a place to hide.
Of course.
It's an honor.
We're from the suburbs
of Ninjago City.
You've probably saved our lives
more times than we can count.
Our son,
he loved you all so much.
How did your Ninja survive
the obliteration of the Merge?
There was no obliteration.
Lee's been lying to you.
Hmm.
We'd started to suspect that,
to be honest.
So the Merge didn't really
destroy the outside world?
No. In fact, it brought
all the realms together.
Ninjago survived,
and so did someone else...
your son.
[gasping]
Arin's... alive?
Oh! [crying and laughing]
[ground rumbling]
[grunting with effort]
There must be a whole skeleton
down there!
You've got to be kidding me.
There's more?
Take a break, you two.
You're gonna burn out.
[gasping]
[groaning]
[ground rumbling and cracking]
No, no! We're losing ground!
[straining]
I can't keep this up!
[grunting and gasping]
You've hit hard pack...
but don't worry, I'm here.
H'yah! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Maybe we can do this after all.
In my vision,
the Source Dragons were talking
like ThunderFang
was still alive,
but Arin released the souls
that empowered him.
We saw ThunderFang turn to dust.
Yeah, yeah,
sounds like a big problem.
I'm thinking about
our small problem.
Mr. Ball-of-Handsome there
is looking more rested
by the second,
and then he's gonna start
tentacling our brains.
How do we get out?
Oh, wait, I got it!
Ah, should've
thought of this before!
What is that?
Our escape!
Wait for it...
[chuckling awkwardly]
[snoring]
[WyldFyre grunting]
What's taking so long?
Just work!
[groaning in frustration]
You stupid thing!
H'yah!
[gate clanking open]
Yes! Plan B worked!
"Plan B"?
You just hurled that thing
in anger.
Hurling stuff in anger
is always my Plan B,
even when it's also my Plan A.
Come on!
[♪♪♪]
Arin's been searching for you
ever since the Merge happened.
We came here to find you.
So Arin's here too?
He, uh...
His investigation took him
in another direction.
[Jay scoffs]
Well, we've actually
been doing
a little investigation
of our own.
We call it the "Mystery
of the Mood-Changing Neighbors."
Barry and I have been
suspicious of Lee's story
for a while,
but anyone
who openly questions Lee
disappears,
and comes back days later
with all their doubts... gone.
Mm-hmm.
You think Lee
is doing something to them?
Altering their minds?
Jay, you said
the Administration checked
for all kinds of mind control.
They did.
On a wide scale,
but if Lee's
only using it selectively
on one or two people,
the Administration
wouldn't have detected it.
What's the Administration?
Let's worry about
one thing at a time.
There's an off-limits
backstage area
in this cavern.
We think Lee's
bringing the neighbors there.
[Jay] We've been back there.
It was definitely weird,
but we didn't see
any kidnappees.
Might be worth looking
with Barry and Jenny's help.
Maybe that's where Lloyd
and Wyldfyre are.
Okay,
so this backstage entrance
sees the most activity,
but we haven't been able
to break in.
Leave that to me.
This won't take long.
I just... want to say goodbye.
Take all the time
you need, Arin.
[gasping]
What?
Are their graves empty?
If my parents aren't here,
where are they?
[Barry] Bad neighbors
are brought here.
Sometimes it's days
before they come out again.
I can easily take out
two guards,
but alerting one Lee
alerts all Lees.
Yup, many bodies, one mind.
Jenny and I will lure him away
while you and Barry sneak in.
Be careful.
You too.
Excuse me,
aren't those the Bad Neighbors
you're looking for?
[wailing dramatically] Whoa!
Thanks!
It's neighbors like you
that give neighbors a good name.
I gotta admit,
you're different
than I thought you'd be.
[Jay] We knew each other?
Well, not personally,
but the Ninja are famous.
My son had a poster of you
up on his wall,
and my wife was a big fan
of your old game show.
Why would a Ninja
host a game show?
That sounds fake.
[crackling]
[beeping]
And Arin said
one time you got trapped
in a videogame...
[laughing] and became
a rocking superstar!
Oh, and when--
[Jay] Now you're just
making things up.
Sorry, but this area
is for cast members only.
It's off-limits to Neighbors.
Not for any secret,
nefarious reason--
[crashing]
[roaring]
What are you doing here?
Uh, rescuing you.
[snorting] I rescued me.
And him.
[gasping]
You knocked out a Lee.
Lee will not like that.
More of him
will already be on the way.
[gasping] You're Arin's dad!
You have no idea
how good it is to meet you.
Hey, the Legendary Green Ninja!
Intros later!
Things are about to get
way Lee up in here!
So glad you and Jay
had each other
through the Merge.
Don't know what Barry and I
would have done
without each other.
Funny you say that.
I only just found Jay.
He lost his memories,
and doesn't even remember
who I am.
Really?
That's not
what his body language says,
and as an amateur detective,
I study body language.
What does his body language
tell you?
That maybe his mind
doesn't remember you,
but his heart sure does.
[alerts beeping]
[gasping]
[Lees] Neighbors!
Please return to your homes
for an emergency,
um, street cleaning.
[Neighbors murmuring]
We need to meet up with Nya
and get to the elevator.
What about
the other residents?
Not paying me
to rescue everyone.
Imposters!
Here to ruin everything!
This is all
just so unneighborly!
[clamoring angrily]
Guess the only way out
is through.
Love that!
Eat fireball, Lee! H'yah!
[yelping]
I'm starting to like you.
Ah!
H'yah! [grunting]
Ah! Oof!
Guess I'll never get to finish
that needlepoint class
I started.
I... I don't understand.
Where'd those guys come from?
Beats me!
Maybe they have some answers!
Hey, you guys!
What's going on?
Oh, no, you don't!
An elevator shaft?
[clanking]
[♪♪♪]
What?
This place is amazing,
but probably evil,
given our luck.
[crowd clamoring below]
Look, some kind of street fight.
Are those... the Ninja?
-H'yah!
-Ah!
Ow!
[grunts of pain and impact]
[grunting]
The Lees can out-teamwork us.
We have to divide
their attention!
For once, don't work together!
I do my best work solo.
H'yah!
[dragon snarling]
[beeping]
[Lee groaning]
I'll be taking this, thank you.
[Lee yelping] Whoa!
[Lees yelping] Whoa-oh!
[Lees yelping]
[♪♪♪]
If the Ninja are here,
they're helping people...
what I should have been doing
instead of following Ras.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
You only did that
for your parents.
My parents!
Yeah, that's what I said.
No, look!
My parents!
Lloyd found them.
[smashing]
Whoa! You okay, Mister?
How'd you get here?
Not really the best time
to start
a New Neighbor Orientation,
but okay.
♪ Perhaps you're
feeling in the dumps... ♪
Yeah, let's wait
until I can get my other bodies
to harmonize.
It'll sound much better.
"Other bodies"?
[ground rumbling,
straining with effort]
I think... this is... it!
[all roaring and straining]
[gasping]
You did it!
[panting] We... did it.
This dragon
makes the Firstbourne
look like a pup.
It can only be
one thing, right?
The remains
of a dead Source Dragon.
Whoa!
[gasping]
Huh?
What was once lost...
can now be found...
Master Wu?
[shouting]
[slamming and grunting]
Greetings, Neighbor!
Just going door to door
assuring Neighbors
that everything is fine.
Oh, uh, one moment.
[grunting]
Nothing to worry about.
[yelping]
[Lloyd] This isn't
getting us anywhere.
[Jay] Speak for yourself!
Whoa!
[gasping]
Aah!
[groaning] I should have
seen that coming.
I'm gonna punch you so hard!
Like a single punch
could take down
a stone-cold warrior like me!
That's cheating.
[screaming]
Why... isn't...
this... thing... working?
[smashing]
Aah!
[thudding heavily]
Why'd you save me?
You're from the outside world.
You don't need me.
I need you not to be crushed.
Why?
'Cause a nice, normal person
wants people to be okay,
and not be crushed
by falling debris.
You don't spend a lot of time
with other people or something?
[Lee] I never met another person
until the Merge.
Did you build this place?
Why?
Because I need people.
For so, so long,
in the Realm of Lee,
there was only Lee.
And Lee, and Lee,
and Lee...
I tried to keep myself busy,
but no matter how many bodies
I created,
there was only just me.
Just Lee.
Then one day,
something remarkable happened.
I didn't know it at first,
but the Realm of Lee
merged with other realms.
Lee was no longer alone.
[grunting with effort]
[gasping]
Where... where am I?
You're in Lee, of course!
Wait, are there
other places to be?
He was the first Non-Lee
I had ever met,
a whole other person
who had thoughts
that weren't my thoughts.
Games are so much more fun
when you don't know
what the other player
is going to do!
[laughing]
Life was all new.
[laughing] Wha! Whoa!
Whuh-oh!
[laughing] Oh!
I realized
other people must be the key
to being happy.
He told me
of the outside world,
its wonders,
and what he missed...
until one day,
he missed them so much,
he left Lee.
I stayed,
because there is no Lee
without... Lee.
[rain pouring]
Right then,
I vowed to make
the Land of Lee so perfect,
no one would ever
want to leave again.
[battle continuing]
And I succeeded!
Why else
would the Administration
dump its unwanteds here?
I painted a wonderful
rainbow of lies
so my new Neighbors
wouldn't ever be curious
about what's outside,
but these new outsiders
want to wash it all away!
I won't let those Ninja
take my friends from me!
I was alone once, too.
A single lie
pushed away
the first real friend
I ever made.
Friends shouldn't
lie to friends,
ever,
but especially on, like,
a city-wide level.
Well, if you have
a way of making friends
that doesn't involve
mass deception and brainwashing,
I'd like to hear it.
[grunting with impact]
Nya, one of us has to
grab Arin's parents and go--
Oh, no, where are
Barry and Jenny?
So you came here for those two?
Then I'll be sure
to keep them here forever!
No!
Another Ninja?
I don't know this color.
He must be new.
[grunting]
I am a good friend.
I am a good friend!
No, you're not being
a good friend right now,
but you can be.
Tell everyone the truth.
Let them go if they want,
and maybe some will stay,
and those will be real friends.
I've only been here
a few minutes,
and I think the Land of Lee
is pretty amazing.
You-you do?
For real?
[♪♪♪]
Mom? Dad?
Arin!
[sobbing joyfully]
A new neighbor?
The Administration
always drops them off
above ground.
Whatever you are,
get away from me!
[spectral tone sounding]
Is that... music?
Oh, no.
Not here. Not now.
[wraiths shrieking]
[spectral horn blowing]
[Lees all moaning]
Look around and see...
in the land of Lee...
...look around...
[spectral horn blowing]